A lot of time went by between when you had your stroke and when i was born
从你中风到我出生，中间过了很长一段时间。
What were you thinking during that time
那段时间你在想什么？
I was just thinking we're gonna make it
我一直在想，我们一定能挺过去。
We're gonna make it
我们一定能挺过去。
At one point when i was pregnant
有一段时间我怀孕了，
They were like are you going to terminate the baby or not it's risky to continue for your health
医生说：你要不要终止妊娠？继续下去对你的健康有风险，
For the baby's health
对宝宝的健康也有风险。
And i was like of course we're gonna keep the baby
我说，当然要留下这个宝宝。
And you have so much trouble making decisions about everything under the sun
而你，什么事都难以做决定，
You know you have trouble deciding what breakfast cereal
连早餐吃什么麦片都要想半天。
No , i do
没有，我真的会。
I do
我真的会。
That is true
这倒是真的。
But i felt so strongly you were supposed to be here
但我心里特别强烈地感觉到，你就应该来到这个世界。
I was just thinking like
我当时只是想着
I wanna be your mother
我想成为你的妈妈，
I wanna be your mother so bad
我太想成为你的妈妈了。
Do you want to tell us about the stroke
你愿意跟我们讲讲那次中风的事吗？
It was a sy night
那是一个忙碌的夜晚，
And as the night progressed
随着夜越来越深，
I noticed my leg was giving out
我发现我的腿开始不听使唤。
And you have an older sibling
你还有一个哥哥姐姐，
So i start thinking like i gotta get him in the bed
于是我想：我得先把他哄上床睡觉。
And i feel bad
我心里很过意不去，
But i heaved them into the cage
但我把他塞进了笼子里。
You meant crib , right
你是说婴儿床，对吧？
Oh what i say , cage
哎，我说的是笼子？
Ha ha ha . i did
哈哈哈，对，你说的是笼子。
Yes
是的。
Thank you
谢谢你。
You know , it was probably a teenager before
你知道吗，我大概到十几岁的时候才意识到
i realize that not everyone has traumatic brain injuries
并不是每个人都有创伤性脑损伤的，
And that's not just some fun gave me
那不只是妈妈给我的某种特别天赋，
And my mom play when she forgets words
而是她偶尔忘词时说出来的样子。
But i always knew that you risked your life
但我一直知道，你为了让我来到这个世界，冒了生命危险。
so that i could come into this world
为了让我来到这个世界。
That was always in the background
这件事一直埋在我心里。
You had said that it made you feel pressure
你说过，这让你感到一种压力。
Yeah
是的。
But pressure to do amazing things with your life
但那是一种要用自己的人生去做出非凡事情的压力。
That's not a bad thing
这也没什么不好的。
Yes
是的。
But i never want amazing things like become the president of the united states
但我所说的非凡，不是去当美国总统
Or go to the moon
或者登上月球，
but like that you would bring joy to people
而是你能给身边的人带去快乐。
Because you have such a kind heart
因为你有一颗善良的心，
And you're such a good person
你是个好人。
I mean , had a pretty good example that's good to hear
嗯，我有一个很好的榜样，这让我很高兴听到这些话。
Thanks l
谢谢你。
You're so strong inside
你内心非常坚强，
And if people see you
但如果别人看到你，
They might not know that because you're so quiet and topful
可能不会意识到，因为你总是那么安静、体贴。
If you weren't here with us
如果你不在我们身边，
The world would not be it's kind of a place
这个世界就不会是现在这个温暖的样子。
Really , truly
真的，发自内心地说。
I can't think of it
我无法想象，
It was a miracle that the two of us made it
我们两个都能活下来，真是一个奇迹。